Rakesh Peela

Software Development Engineer-I (Frontend)

Email: <u>rakhi2104@gmail.com</u> Contact: +91 99852 96699

GitHub: https://github.com/rakhi2104 LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/rakesh-peela

Summary

Innovative, creative and committed Frontend developer with a good eye for design and vision for product. I have around 2 years of experience building reactive web applications with real-time data. I am constantly learning and keen to gain more experience in frontend and application development and an occasional Open Source contributor. I also love exploring and implementing UI/UX principles into building products accessible by everyone.

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: JavaScript (Vanilla, ES6, TypeScript), Python
- Databases: MongoDB, SQL
- Operating Systems: Linux, Windows
- Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, NodeJS, ReactJS
- Web Frameworks: GatsbyJS, ExpressJS
- Graphic Design Software: Figma, Adobe Creative Suite
- Cloud Platforms: Google Cloud Platform, Zeit, DigitalOcean
- Other Technologies: Redux, Docker, CI/CD, GraphQL, React Native, GoLang

Work Experience

Software Development Engineer (Frontend)

Sureify Labs Inc., Hyderabad Office

(July 2020 - present)

Sureify's Lifetime platform is a modular SaaS solution for the life and annuity industry that helps carriers acquire, service, and engage their customers. I majorly contribute in

- → Building no/low-code tool for Insurance Admins to easily customize their end-user facing servicing application with ease.
- → Developing backend driven UI components which involve highly customisable internal Design Systems and modelled using React and Redux.
- → Mentoring freshers to kickstart their career in Frontend development

Software Development Engineer (Frontend)

Apxor Technology Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Hyderabad

(May 2019 - Jul 2020)

Apxor is a complete product intelligence platform to understand user intent and deliver customized experiences to the user, increasing user retention and revenue. As the Frontend Developer, my activities include

- → Designing, architecting and implementing Shared-Sign-On for business partners to integrate.
- → Redesigning the UI/UX and developing the "Walkthroughs workflow" which was earlier inoperable by customers. The new flow resulted in customers creating multifold campaigns on their own and allowing customers to take necessary actions to keep their users engaged.
- → Revamping the existing WordPress website to a static website using Webflow.
- → Migrating the existing Blog to a performant static site using GatsbyJS and content using Ghost CMS.

Remote Machine Learning Intern

Siya Softicon Pvt. Ltd.

(April 2018 - August 2018)

- → Setup 2-GPU cluster with Tensorflow, Keras and other technologies and implemented DC-GANs to generate FMCG Package designs.
- → Prepare classification models for classifying Fire Ants, readings on a <u>Digital</u> thermometer and analog pressure gauges.

Machine Learning Engineering Intern

Solivar Labs Pvt. Ltd.

(May 2018 - September 2018)

→ Developed a web application to predict disease from Chest X-Ray using Django and Keras. Also prototyped "Neural Style Transfer" using Keras and Tensorflow winning the best Capstone Project

Projects

• Serverless Group Chat Application (qszh-qvp.firebaseapp.com)

• Several other side projects can be found on github.com/rakhi2104

Achievements & Certifications

Awarded MVP (Most Valuable Professional) for my contributions to Open Source
 Mattermost tools (v5.24)

https://developers.mattermost.com/contribute/mvp

June 16, 2020

Go: The Complete Developer's Guide (Golang)
 Udemy

Certificate
Mar 2021

 Multiplatform Mobile App Development with React Native Coursera NKW8N5LZCMPC Sep 2020

MongoDB for JavaScript Developers

MongoDB University

• APIs and Microservices using NodeJS

<u>FreeCodeCamp</u>

Academic Qualifications

Qualification	Institution	University	Year of Passing	Percentage of Marks / CGPA
B.Tech [CSE]	Gayatri Vidya Parishad College of Engineering (A)	J.N.T.U. (Kakinada)	2019	7.39 out of 10.00

Talks

"Going Serverless from Zero to Hero
- using Firebase and Google Cloud
Functions" at Google Women Tech
Makers meetup - IWD'19 at Vizag

Hobbies

- Playing Badminton
- Exploring and experimenting different UI/UX inspirations

Online Presence

Dribbble: https://dribbble.com/rakhi2104
Twitter: https://twitter.com/RAKHI_2104